Free your mind.
The Animatrix is a animation, science fiction film directed by Peter Chung.
Straight from the creators of the groundbreaking Matrix trilogy, this collection of short animated films from the world's leading anime directors
fuses computer graphics and Japanese anime to provide the background of the Matrix universe and the conflict between man and machines.
The shorts include Final Flight of the Osiris, The Second Renaissance, Kid's Story,
Program, World Record, Beyond, A Detective Story and Matriculated.
Neo ("Kid's Story") (voice), played by Keanu Reeves.
Trinity ("Kid's Story" and "A Detective Story")
(voice), played by Carrie-Anne Moss.
The Kid ("Kid's Story") (voice), played by Clayton Watson.
Jue ("Final Flight of the Osiris") / Manabu
("Beyond") (voice), played by Pamela Adlon.
Alexa ("Matriculated") (voice), played by Melinda Clarke.
Crew Man ("Final Flight of the Osiris") / Kaiser
("Program") (voice), played by John DiMaggio.
The Animatrix (Japanese: アニマトリックス, Hepburn: Animatorikkusu) is a 2003 adult
animated science fiction anthology film produced by the Wachowskis.
The anime compiles nine animated short films, detailing the backstory of The Matrix film series, in
addition to providing side stories that expand the universe and tie into the film series.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and fans.
The film explores themes of martial arts, artificial
intelligence (a.i.), hacker, virtual reality, dystopia.
The tone is thought_provoking.